Finding Aid for the Knox Mellon Collection of Material About the John Birch Society and Other Radical Conservative Organizations and Causes LSC.1102
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books
  - Bullets and confetti - from the pages of American Opinion. Boston & Los Angeles: Western Islands., 1961 (Box 8)
  - Collectivism in the churches. Wheaton, Illinois: Church League of America., 1956 (Box 7)
  - The web of subversion. New York: John Day Company., 1954 (Box 8)
  - National Review Reader. New York: The bookmailer., 1957 (Box 7)
  - Your health - your sanity in the age of treason... Quakertown, Pennsylvania: Humanitarian Society., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Democracy versus communism. Princeton, New Jersey: Institute of fiscal and political education., 1957 (Box 8)
  - Constitutional crisis ... introduction by Congressman Dale Alford. New York: Speller., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Martin Dies' story. New York: Bookmailer., 1963 (Box 8)
  - The coming showdown. Boston: Little., 1942 (Box 12)
  - While you slept. New York: Devin-Adair., 1958 (Box 11)
  - 'Fools gold'. An expose of un-American activities and political action in the United States since 1860 by 'The senator from Alaska'. New York: Madison & Marshall., 1936 (Box 11)
  - Toward Soviet America. Balboa, California: Elgin Publications., 1961 (Box 8)
  - The welfare staters. New York: Freedom Press., 1962 (Box 8)
  - Strange fire., 1954 (Box 6)
  - The conscience of a conservative. Shepherdsville, Kentucky: Victor Publishing Company., 1960 (Box 11)
  - The tragedy of Bolivia. New York: Devin-Adair., 1958 (Box 11)
  - The road to serfdom. Chicago: University of Chicago., 1944 (Box 11)
  - Masters of deceit. New York: Holt., 1958 (Box 12)
  - America swings to the left. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company., 1933 (Box 11)
  - Workers' paradise lost. New York: Funk & Wagnalls., 1967 (Box 7)
  - America's retreat from victory. New York: Devin-Adair., 1954 (Box 6)
  - "Major speeches and debates of.. ." Reprinted from The Congressional Record. Washington D.C.: G.P.O., 1950-51 (Box 12)
  - Russia and the peace. Mew York: MacMillan., 1944 (Box 6)
  - Brain washing in the high schools. New York: Devin-Adair., 1959 (Box 12)
  - Barry Goldwater: freedom is his flight plan. Foreward by Clarence Budington Kelland. New York: Fleet., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Spies and traitors. New York: Prentice-Hall, Incorporated., 1945 (Box 6)
  - The naked communist. Saly Lake City: Ensign Publishing Company., 1958 (Box 7)
  - The hope of the world. Dallas: Miller., 1958; (2 copies) (Box 7)
  - The Maurice and Laura Folk Foundation. Pittsburgh: Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania., 1966 (Box 7)
  - Red Fascism. Los Angeles: Federal Printing Company., 1947; (2 copies) (Box 6)
  - The liberation of Italy., n.d. (Box 6)
- Various Pamphlets, Leaflets, Brochures, etc., 1950's-60's
  - Soviet world outlook. A handbook of communist statements., 1959 (Box 15)
  - Manual for Americanism workshop. "The ideals of American Heritage." American Legion., November 1961-February 1962 (Box 17)
  - "The Real threat of communism." American Economic Foundation., November 15, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Heads Up. "Dedicated to fight communism"., February 1964 (Box 18)
  - The Fulton Lewis Jr. report on the fund for the republic. (Box 21)
  - Does the American Civil Liberties Union serve the communist cause? What do you think?, November 1961 (Box 21)
  - The key to the constitution of the United States., 1956 (Box 21)
  - Handbook for "Summit.", 1960 (Box 21)
  - "My reasons for opposing fluoridation.", n.d. (Box 21)
  - The "Left Swing" in education. Including left-wing traps for youth., n.d. (Box 21)
  - Various pamphlets, leaflets and brochures dealing with communism, immigration, democracy and foreign aid., 1944-67 (Box 21)
  - Various pamphlets, leaflets and brochures on socialism, communism, segregation, education and Earl Warren., 1936-65 (Box 22)
  - Various pamphlets, brochures, leaflets, articles and clippings on a wide variety of different causes., 1950's-60's (Box 23)
  - 90 miles to hell. The rape of a nation. Jack Brady Associates., 1959 (Box 23)
  - American Opinion pamphlets., 1961-62 (Box 24)
  - Various pamphlets, brochures, leaflets, articles newspapers and clippings on a wide variety of different causes., 1950's-60's (Box 24)
  - The United States as a communist nation... under which flag? Statement of Austin T. Fleet., March 4, 1958 (Box 24)
  - A business man looks at communism, by an American business man., January 1961 (Box 24)
  - "The truth about the Foreign Policy Association.", 1960 (Box 28)
  - Does the American Civil Liberties Union serve the communist cause? What do you think?, 1962 (Box 29)
- Periodicals
  - One Man's Opinion., 1956-57 (Box 9)
    vol.1, no.1 (February 1956).
    vol.1, no.5 (November 1956).
    vol.2, no.6-10 (February-November 1957).
  - American Opinion., 1958-60 (Box 9)
    vol.1, no.1, 5, 7, 10 (1958).
    vol.2, no.1, 2, 6-11 (1959).
    vol.3, no.1-10 (1960).
    vol.4, no.1-11 (1961).
  - American Opinion., 1962-68 (Box 10)
    vol.5, no.1-3, 5-11 (1962).
    vol.6, no.1-5, 7-10 (1963)
    vol.7, no.7 (1964).
    vol.8, no.2-7 (1965)
    vol.10, no.2, 5, 7-8 (1967)
    vol.11, no.2, 5 (1968).
  - Town Hall., 1966-68 (Box 13)
    vol.28, no.37 (September 13, 1966).
    vol.29, no.1, 3-4, 6-7, 10, 13-14, 18-19, 22-25, 27, 29-31, 33-35, 37-38, 40-49, 52 (1967).
    vol.30, no.1-3, 5, 9-11 (1968).
  - The Dan Smoot Report., 1964-68 (Box 17)
  - Latin America Report., 1966-68 (Box 18)
  - Liberty Letter published by Liberty Lobby., 1966-68 (Box 18)
  - Liberty Line. Bellingham, Washington., 1967 (Box 18)
  - Liberty Lobby., 1963-65 (Box 18)
  - Liberty Lowdown, published by Liberty Lobby., 1966-67 (Box 18)
  - The Manion Forum, South Bend, Indiana., 1967-68 (Box 18)
  - News and Views. Eternal vigilance is forever the price of freedom., June 1962 (Box 18)
  - A review of the news., n.d. (Box 19)
  - Correction, please!, July 18, 1964 (Box 19)
  - New Individualist Review., April 1961 (Box 19)
  - Foreign Affairs. An American quarterly review (vol.40, no.3)., April 1962 (Box 19)
  - Free America. A magazine to promote independence., June 1939 (Box 19)
  - Don Bell reports. Palm Beach, Florida., 1958, 1960 (Box 19)
  - Problems of Communism (vol.12, no.1-3, 5)., 1963 (Box 19)
  - Soviet Highlights (vol.1, no.1)., 1959 (Box 19)
  - Scoop (vol.2, no.27)., November 1941 (Box 19)
  - The Freeman. A monthly journal of ideas on liberty., 1964-68 (Box 19)
    vol.14, no.5, 8 (1964).
    vol.17, no.8-10 (1967).
    vol.18, no.2-3 (1968).
  - Manion Forum. Various issues., 1964-66 (Box 29)